本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： vernie 熊猫大虾 Virus Killer HTC Cinderella
校对： Cinderella    后期： 泡面小小
要是传出去 你毁了一份
If it gets out that you destroyed a file
有关一个共产党间谍的文件
relating to a potential communist sleeper agent,
你的前途就毁了
your career will be over.
你要我帮你监视中情局?
You want me to spy on the CIA for you?
弗兰克 我喜欢上别人了 我要搬出去
Frank, I've met someone. I'm moving out.
- 是谁 克莱尔? - 山姆・卡拉汉
- Who is it, Claire? - Sam Callaghan.
你觉得那会长久吗?
You think that will last?
- 安吉・沃诺克 很高兴见到你 - 你好
- Ange Warnock. Pleased to meet you. - Yeah, g'day.
- 我们得谈谈 - 她想成为记者 很不错
- We have to talk. - Wannabe journalist.She's good.
我在一群孩子中长大
I was around a lot of kids growing up.
在樟宜? 是的
In Changi? Yeah.
抱歉 我不是有意说起那个的
Sorry, I didn't mean to bring that up.
不!
No!
我本来约了山姆见面 但是他还没回来
I was supposed to meet Sam but he hasn't come back yet.
他没事吧?
Is he alright?
至少几小时内他哪儿都去不了
He won't be going anywhere for a few hours.
这行不通的 你不属于这儿
It's not going to work. You don't belong here.
不要离开弗兰克 你还没告诉他 对吧?
Don't leave Frank. You haven't told him yet, have you?
- 所以你仍然可以... - 没错
- So you can still... - Yeah, of course.
- 你必须尝尝这些 - 没门!
- You've got to try one of these. - No way!
额! 那是一只脚!
Eugh! It's a foot!
试一下 你必须得尝一下
Try one. You've got to try.
这很好吃 真的好吃 来吧 尝尝吧
It's good, it's good. It's really good. Come on, come on.
- 你要敢于冒险 - 不要!
- You've gotta be adventurous. - No!
来吧 就试一下 就尝一点点
Come on, just try. Just taste just a little bit.
来吧 勇敢一点
Come on. Be brave.
这好恶心
That is terrible.
我知道 所以给你吃啊
I know. That's why I gave it to you.
我是不会吃的
I wouldn't eat it.
- 你!- 哎哟!
- You! - Ow!
现在是六十年代 罗伯
It's the '60s, Robbo.
我们能做一切想做的事
We can do whatever we want.
安吉
Ange.
石龙岗之路 第一季第09集
两个警官巡逻的时候发现他在街上游荡
Two officers on patrol found him wandering on the street
就在那女孩公寓外面
just outside the girl's apartment.
他身上有血 她的
He had blood on him. Hers.
绝对是安吉莉卡・沃诺克
It's definitely Angelica Warnock,
公爵的酒保
the bartender from the Duke.
她是一个兼职记者
She was a part-time journalist.
是的 她被刺伤了 有人看到什么了吗?
Yeah, she's been stabbed. Anyone see anything?
是他干的 山姆
He did it, Sam.
唯一的疑问是... 他为什么要找你?
The only mystery...why would he ask for you?
他是一个老朋友
Oh, he's an old mate.
我要指控你的朋友谋杀
I'm charging your mate with murder.
山姆
Sam.
我的天啊 罗伯 你没事吧?
Bloody hell, Robbo. You alright?
到底发生了什么?
What the hell happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
伙计 不 我认真的
Mate, no, I mean it.
安吉和我
Ange and me.
在武吉士
Great night.
很棒的夜晚
Bugis Street.
- 吃了些东西 - 你喝酒了吗?
- Some food. - Were you drinking?
就喝了一点 但我不太能喝酒
Well, just a little, but I'm not much of a drinker.
嗯
Yeah.
然后我醒来的时候 她躺在我身边
And then I woke up and she was laying there beside me.
她是个好姑娘 山姆
She's a good girl, Sam.
我真的很喜欢她
I really liked her.
你喜欢她?
You liked her?
是的 发展得不错
Well, yeah, it was heading that way.
我都不记得我们有没有做过
I can't even remember if we did it.
我不知道我想让你帮我干什么 山姆
I don't know what I'm asking you to do for me, Sam.
我不是凶手
I'm not a killer.
抓到你了 杀人犯
Got you, you prick.
准备好上头版吧
Say hello to page one.
我得给那个女孩的尸体鉴定身份
I had to ID that poor girl's body.
我本该说些什么
I should have said something.
应该提醒她的
Should have warned her.
所以你看到他们在一起了?
So you saw them together?
他昨晚在酒吧把她载走了
He picked her up at the pub last night.
我应该... 要是我跟她说了就好了
I should... If only I'd said something to her.
他说了他们在交往
He just said that they'd been seeing each other.
是啊 把她灌醉再和她上床...
Yeah, fill her full of grog and get her laid, that's...
我认识罗伯二十年了 他不可能是凶手
I've known Robbo 20 years. The guy's no killer.
- 他跟你说了什么? - 他不记得了
- What'd he say to you? - He doesn't remember.
好吧 这消息真有价值
Oh, well, that's priceless.
我只想说
All I'm saying is
你应该确定好情况再发报道
you really want to be sure about this before you file it.
我已经报道了 伙计
I've already filed it, mate.
这是后续跟进
This is the follow-up.
我会竭尽全力让那个混蛋被绞死
I will do everything in my power to see that prick hang.
你有没有...
Have you...
你看见我爸爸了吗?
Have you seen my dad?
你看见我爸爸了吗 詹姆士・卡拉汉少校?
Have you seen my dad, Major James Callaghan?
卡拉汉少校 他在这里吗?
Major Callaghan, do you know if he's here?
你看见我爸爸了吗?
Have you seen my dad?
他叫詹姆士・卡拉汉
His name's James Callaghan.
打扰一下 你看见我爸爸了吗?
Excuse me, have you seen my dad?
你在找谁呢 孩子?
Who are you looking for, son?
我认识他 之前见过他 但不是和女孩在一起
I know him. Seen him before. Not with girl, though.
他们看起来很好
They look good together.
他很高大英俊
He's a big guy, handsome.
但是她身材很娇小
Mm, but she's so little.
他们怎么走到一起的呢?
How they fit together?
很有意思
Interesting.
你觉得她当时快乐吗? 我的意思是...
You think she was happy? I mean...
- 什么? - 他没有强迫她 是吗?
- Ah, what? - He wasn't forcing her, was he?
不不不 没有
No, no, no, no.
他们在接吻
They are kissing.
- 接吻? - 看起来很幸福
- Kissing? - Mm. Seem very happy.
挽着手 很快乐
Arms together, having good times.
他们走了哪条路?
Which way did they go?
来回酒吧的路
Um... Came from bar, go to bar.
黑莲花?
Black Lotus?
- 可能是 - 好的 谢谢 大娘
- Maybe. - Alright. Thanks, Aunty.
喂 山姆 山姆 山姆 山姆!
Hey, Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam!
也许有一天我们俩能在一起呢 哈?
Maybe you and me can fit together, one day, hmm?
是啊 有可能
Yeah. Maybe, yeah.
安吉? 没错 我认识她
Angie? Sure, I know her.
她昨晚来过这儿吗?
Was she here last night?
来过 和一个高大的老男人一起来的
She was here, with a big older guy.
好像是澳洲人
Aussie, I think.
- 他们在喝酒吗? - 可能喝了一杯
- Were they drinking? - Maybe one.
然后他们就走了
And then they left.
知道他们从哪条路走的吗?
Any idea which way they went?
我经常在这儿看到她
I've seen her around here a lot.
她是个记者 对吗?
She was a reporter, right?
算是吧
Well, sort of, yeah.
她为了付房租在公爵那里工作
She worked at the Duke to pay the rent.
她想成为一名一流记者 时代杂志的
She wants to be a big-time reporter. Times Magazine.
她觉得这一切都很有异国情调
She thinks all this is exotic.
就像背包客那样
Like the backpackers.
下了船 来到这里
Come off boat, find their way here.
蟑螂和老鼠 异国情调
Cockroaches and rats. Exotic.
这里不适合一个白人女孩问问题 是吗?
It's not really the place for a white girl to ask questions though, is it?
大多数时候 是没关系的
Most of the time, it's OK.
不过一旦有麻烦 就会来势汹汹
But when trouble happens, it happens fast.
你觉得安吉惹上麻烦了?
You think Ange was in trouble?
这儿待的时间长了 总会惹上麻烦的
You stay here long enough, trouble finds you eventually.
嘿 再请我喝杯酒
Hey, buy me another drink
我会帮你找出安吉是不是惹上麻烦了
and I'll help you find out if trouble found Angie.
美好的一天啊 不是吗 哈里森?
Lovely day, isn't it, Harrison?
不不不 我们不这么做
Oh, no, no, no. We don't do it like that.
我们看看海鲜 挑选我们中意的鱼
We look at the seafood, we select the fish of our choice.
嘿 看那一条
Hey, look at that one.
很美味
Yum-yum. Mmm.
我们聊聊蟋蟀
We talk about the cricket.
当然 不是会钻箱子那种
Well, not in your case.
我们两位绅士在充满异域情调的
Um... We're two gentlemen taking
亚洲风光下聊天
in the exotic Asian surrounds.
我们能不能赶紧完事儿?
Can we just get this over and done with?
好吧 有个问题
Well, therein lies the problem.
我能说这是一个哲学问题吗?
May I suggest it's a philosophical problem?
你得喜欢你做的事 哈里森
You've got to love what you do, Harrison.
既然做了就要喜欢它 要么就不做
Either do something and embrace it, or don't do it at all.
如果你做一些自己讨厌的事
If you do something you hate,
它会从内心消耗你
it'll eat you up from the inside.
好的 谢谢 我会记住的
OK, thank you. I'll, er, I'll keep that in mind.
哈里森?
Ah, Harrison?
还有一件小事需要你帮我做
There is one more little thing you can do for me.
越南
Vietnam.
越南?
Vietnam?
那是国家安全委员会的机密文件
That's NSC-classified material.
如果我要去拿那个文件
If I were to get that information,
我就得潜入怀尔德・比尔的办公室
I'd have to break into Wild Bill's office.
这个任务对你来说肯定不在话下
Well, a challenge surely within your skill set.
获取新加坡情报 这事我能办到
Sharing intel on Singapore, that's one thing.
但是越南?
But Vietnam?
不管怎样我们都会拿到这个情报的
Well, it's information we're going to get anyway.
怀尔德・比尔可能在月底前
Wild Bill will probably tell me
就会告诉我这个情报
by the end of the month.
那你为什么不直接去问他呢?
Well, why don't you just ask him, then?
怀尔德・比尔做事太老派
Wild Bill is old-school.
而你和我 我们引领的是新潮流
You and me, we're the new wave.
我们办事当机立断 直截了当
We can get things done on the ground, mano a mano,
犯不着跟官僚纠缠
without being tangled up in bureaucracy.
你知道 你没必要威胁我
You know, you don't have to blackmail me.
你把苏玲的资料给我
You could just give me the file on Su Ling
我就会按你所说的做
and I would do what you request anyway.
行啊
Well, I could,
但有时候人需要被指引才会做正确的事情
but sometimes people need to be helped to do the right thing.
安委会的报告 尽快拿到 明白了吗?
That NSC report, as soon as you can, alright?
我就要这条了 谢谢
Ah, I'll take this one, please.
我知道一个事实 温斯顿在被谋杀前
I know for a fact that Winston was fearing for his life
很担心他的生命安全
before he was murdered.
所以你说错了 这不是一次随机抢劫
So this was not a random robbery like you said.
我可以看下那个案件的资料吗?
Is it possible for me to take a look at the case notes?
- 郑太太 - 我真的需要看下那个材料
- Mrs Cheng. - I really do need to look at them.
我不想让你们遗漏任何细节
I don't want you to have missed anything.
郑太太 抱歉 我们不能这样做
Mrs Cheng, I'm sorry. That's not the way we work.
那你们怎么做?
What is the way you work?
我丈夫在你管辖的区域内被谋杀
My husband was murdered on your streets.
什么进展都没有
Nothing has been done about it.
杀害他的凶手还逍遥法外
His killer is out there,
吃喝玩乐 过着潇洒的生活
laughing, drinking, living his life
而温斯顿却只能长眠地下
while Winston lies in his grave.
你让我怎么能安心入眠?
How do you suppose I sleep at night?
你只能在这里看材料
They can't leave the station.
霍克
Ah, Hock.
温斯顿・郑的材料
Winston Cheng's file.
郑太太
Ah, Mrs Cheng.
很抱歉 您丈夫的材料好像不见了
I'm very sorry, but your husband's file appears to be missing.
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
安吉的公寓就在这里
Angie's apartment is just here.
门上锁了
The door's locked.
别 别想了 老兄
No, don't even think about it, man.
你总是小瞧我
You always underestimate me.
才没 我总是高估你
No, I overestimate you.
我觉得你会做得更聪明一点 更低调一点
I think you will do something smarter, and quieter.
更安全一点!
Safer!
不是吧
Come on.
哇哦!
Whoa!
别动 好吗? 别动
Relax, OK? Just relax.
为什么你不拦住他?
Why didn't you stop him?
你以为我没拦么?
What do you think I was doing?
别担心 下次再见到他 我就认出来了
Don't worry. I see him again, I'll know him.
- 是吗? - 没错
- Yeah? - Yeah.
什么掉了?
是他耳朵啦
他到底在找什么呢?
What was he looking for, anyway?
嘿! 拿着啦! 嘿!
Hey! Hey, hold it, lah! Hey!
嘿
Hey.
这些都是什么?
What is all that?
看起来像监视时拍的照片
They look like surveillance photos.
找到一个写满名字和数字的名单
It's a list of names and numbers.
肯定是她在调查的东西
Must be something she was working on.
嘿
Hey.
不管那人找的是什么 肯定不是钱
Whatever that guy was looking for, it's definitely not money.
他肯定在找什么东西
He was definitely looking for something.
康
Kang.
嗯?
Hmm?
是大麻
It's hash.
迈卡
Macca.
没空呢 山姆
Not now, Sam.
我得把这个先打完
I've really got to get this filed.
她在写什么呢 迈卡?
What was she writing, Macca?
她家里到处都是照片 名字和数字
She had photos, names and numbers everywhere.
可我从没看见一份报道
I never saw a story.
她把东西给我了 只是草稿
No, she gave it to me. Rough draft, anyway.
是什么呢?
What was it?
她痴迷于秘密帮派
She was obsessed with the Secret Societies.
想追踪新加坡毒品的交易链
Wanted to track the movement of drugs through Singapore.
我告诉她这事儿没戏
I told her it was a dead-end story.
证据难找 也没证人 就别做了
Hard to prove, no-one to talk to, and to let it go.
她放弃了吗?
Did she?
山姆 这跟你朋友刺杀她又没关系
Sam, this has got nothing to do with your mate stabbing her.
毒品报道跟这无关
The drug story is irrelevant.
那为什么她家里会藏有
Then why was she hiding a trafficable amount of hash
可供买卖量的大麻呢?
in her apartment?
安吉不会沾染毒品的 她不喜欢
Ange would never touch drugs. She hated them.
她只想成为记者
All she ever wanted was to be a journo.
还是去问你朋友大麻是怎么进她家的吧
So you ask your mate how that hash got into her place.
- 得了吧 - 接着说
- Oh, come on. - Go on.
我敢说十有八九毒品是他的
I'll give you ten to one it's his.
他肯定也不会承认
And I'll give you five to one that he lies about it.
而且我确定不管怎样你都会相信他
And I'll give you even money that you'll believe him anyway.
是啊 无所谓了
Yeah, whatever.
不 当然不是
No, absolutely not.
所以你从没在新加坡进行大麻交易?
So you never moved hash in and out of Singapore?
跟我发誓毒品的事跟你无关
Swear to me you're not involved in drugs.
我发誓 真没有
I swear. Never.
因为我看到一个记者
'Cause I'm looking at a reporter
在调查港口的毒品交易
investigating the drug trade on the docks,
也跟一个跑货船的男人在一起
hanging out with a guy who works on freighters.
这都说得通 对吧?
It all adds up, doesn't it?
她的确问了我关于毒品的问题
Well, she asked me questions about it, sure.
我们就是这样见面的
I mean, that's how we met.
她在那里跟船员和港口人员交谈
She's down there talking to sailors and dockies.
那些人嘴巴很严 不干活的时候也不多话
Those blokes don't talk, even if they're not moving stuff.
山姆 如果你想要放弃这个案子我也能理解
Sam, I can understand if you wanna give up.
告诉我这不是你干的
Tell me you didn't do this.
这不是我干的
I didn't do this.
但你也不记得了
But you can't remember.
对
No.
也许这里有什么猫腻 有些互动
Maybe there's something in here, some kind of contact.
我是说 她在挖掘毒品交易内幕
I mean, she's digging into the drug trade.
可能她走得比迈卡想得还远
Maybe she got further than Macca thought.
你是说她在跟踪这个事情 太过头了
You're saying she was following a story, got too close,
以至于她调查的某些人把她杀了
and someone she was investigating killed her.
这个人偷溜进她的房间
And this person sneaked into her room,
绕过睡在她旁边的你朋友 把她捅死
past your friend who was sleeping next to her, stabbed her to death
而你朋友完全没有醒过来?
and your friend didn't wake up?
那些大麻怎么说呢?
And what about the drugs?
可能是调查的一部分
Maybe it was part of the investigation.
- 也许她自己买的 - 买那么多?
- Maybe she bought some. - That much?
有没有可能你朋友在撒谎?
Is it possible you got it wrong about your friend?
所有人都觉得他在撒谎
Everyone thinks he did it.
你回来啦! 这个 你跟他说了吗?
You're back! Here, did you tell him?
还没呢
Not yet.
关于温斯顿叔叔的 案子材料不见了
About Uncle Winston. The missing case file.
这是关于温斯顿什么的?
What's this about Winston?
好的 我会转告他的
Yes, of course. I'll tell him.
澳大利亚高级专员想要见你
The Australian High Commissioner wants to see you.
你先去吧 我晚点告诉你
Well, you go. I'll tell you later.
这得要一整天 所以只要我们...
They're taking all day, so as long as we...
塔克沃思女士
Lady Tuckworth.
辛普森夫人?
Mrs Simpson?
卡拉汉先生
Mr Callaghan.
我这几天住在这儿
I'm just staying here for a few days.
是啊 她丈夫出差了 我陪陪她
Yes, just company while her husband's away.
出门啊?
Heading off?
是啊 我们去买机票
Yes, we're just going to get some tickets.
机票?
Tickets?
是的 克莱尔的母亲生病了
Yes, Claire's mother's been taken ill
她要回悉尼待一段时间
and she's just going to spend a little time in Sydney.
你母亲? 我记得她过世了
Your mother? I was sure she died.
没有 你肯定记错了
No, you must be mistaken.
我丈夫在等你吧
I believe my husband's waiting for you.
很高兴见到你 卡拉汉先生
It's lovely to see you, Mr Callaghan.
我也是
Yes.
那么 你是那个澳大利亚特约记者
Now, you're a mate of this Australian stringer,
布鲁斯・麦克唐纳的朋友吗?
Bruce Macdonald?
迈卡 是的 没错
Ah, Macca, that's right. Yeah, right.
我需要你去告诉他不要这么关注
I need you to tell him to pull his head in
这个被谋杀的女孩的新闻了
over this murdered girl story.
堪培拉正试图敏感对待这些黑色议题
Canberra's trying to be a little bit sensitive to the black issue.
现在公民投票还悬而未决
There's a referendum in the air.
不要因为这件事惹麻烦
So now is not the time to have
现在不是时候
this particular piece of excrement hitting the fan.
跟我相比 他可能更听你的话
Well, he's more likely to listen to you than me.
听着 我不是让他不写这个报道了
Look, I'm not asking him not to write the story, you know,
只是缓和一下
just tone it down a bit.
那个家伙显然罪不可赦
The bloke's obviously as guilty as sin.
先生 我不这么认为
Sir, I don't think he is.
我最近在调查这个情况 我认为不是他杀了她
I've been investigating the situation and I don't think he killed her.
真的吗?
Really?
是啊 你是个侦探
Well, you're a detective
这事根本轮不上我班门弄斧
and far be it for me to tell you how to suck eggs,
但是 有什么证据呢?
but, er, what about the evidence, hmm?
一个原住民
Abo.
喝了酒
Booze.
一个女人 死了
Woman, dead.
罗伯特・科利尔被誉为战争英雄
Robert Collier's a decorated war hero.
真的吗?
Really?
他在三九年入伍
He signed up in '39.
第二陆军部 第二武装部队
WO2, 2nd AIF.
他荣誉地服役 获得了勇敢和服务奖章
He served with distinction. Medals for bravery and service.
这样啊
Right.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
"土著战争英雄被陷害"
'Aboriginal War Hero Framed'.
那可不是我想看到的头条
That's the last headline I want to see.
如果你能释放他 我就能找出事情的真相
Well, if you can get him out, I can find out what really happened.
哈里森
Harrison.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我只是确保我有你想要的文件的拷贝
I was just making sure that I had copies of those files you wanted.
好样的 我现在就看
Oh, good for you. I'll look at 'em right now.
好的
OK.
这样吧 我最好去接电话 一会再和你聊
Actually, I'd better get this. I'll catch up with you later.
- 谢谢 山姆 你好样的 - 这只是保释
- Thanks, Sam, you're a champion. - It's only bail.
在你的听证会之前还有很多事情要做
Got a lot of work before your committal hearing.
因为澳洲政府忙着拉皮条没空伸张正义...
Any comment on getting away with murder because the Australian Government's...
- 迈卡! - 就让犯人逍遥法外...
- Macca! - ...is too busy pandering...
把他带回我那里
Take him back to my place.
对此有什么看法吗?
...to see justice done?
闭嘴！ 你怎么回事?
Shut up! What's wrong with you?
我怎么回事? 他是凶手!
What's wrong with me? He's the killer!
那个人是个战士
That man is a soldier.
他对国家做出的贡献比你想到的都要多
He's done a lot more for his country than you ever will.
别来这一套
Oh, don't tell me.
怎么 这跟你们在樟宜的事有关系吗?
What, is this some bloody Changi thing you two got going on, is it?
- 什么? - 你把那次行动当作奖章
- What? - You wear that camp like a badge.
还是个战士? 那都是二十年前的事了
And a soldier? That was 20 years ago.
别说了 迈卡
Don't start, Macca.
他来澳洲是在逃避什么?
What's he running away from in Australia, huh?
我能找到什么正当理由让他回家吗?
Will I find a warrant out for him back home?
你知道他回去的时候发现了什么吗?
Do you know what he found when he went back?
孩子被带走了 他的妻子也不见了
Kids had been taken, his wife was gone
银行把他们的房子收走了
and the bank had taken their house.
他为国家服役五年 军队甚至不支付他工资
Five years he served his country. The army won't even pay him.
不管什么样的记者都会报道他
Any sort of reporter would write that story.
两杯咖啡
Two coffees.
听起来好像是个对当局不满的人
Sounds like a man that might be a bit shitty with authority.
或许会觉得毒品交易是个好出路
Might find the drug trade a better way to go.
她在调查秘密帮派
She was investigating Secret Societies.
她在码头问问题呢
She's asking questions down on the docks.
说不定她是被黑帮杀害的
Maybe she was killed by a gangster.
你就骗自己吧
Keep telling yourself that.
她告诉你她在做什么了 不是吗?
She told you what she was doing, didn't she?
你没有阻止她 也没有警告她
You never stopped her. You never warned her.
你有没有读过她的文章?
You even read her story?
没有吧? 你根本就是懒得看
No? You couldn't be bothered.
得了吧 她就是个孩子
Nah, come on, she was just a kid.
一个女招待
A barmaid.
难道她能突然间写出普利策一般的作品?
What, she's gonna suddenly write a Pulitzer piece?
这不是重点 或许她在调查什么东西
That's not the point. Maybe she was onto something.
或许这引来了杀身之祸
Maybe that's what's got her killed.
好啦 好啦!
Alright. Alright!
好啦 我会看看的
Alright, I'll read it.
要是我发现什么你能接受吗?
Are you prepared for what I might find?
他住在这里
He lives here.
嘿!
Oi!
不不不 你不能上去 凶手勿进
No, no, no. You no go up. No killer.
韩哥 不要乱讲话 山姆讲可以带他上去的
山姆他没有跟我讲啊
你要上去是吗?
先闯过我这一关
怎么啦?
这是山姆的朋友 罗伯
This is Sam's friend, Robbo.
罗伯特・科利尔
Ah, Robert Collier.
山姆说带他到他的房间里
Sam said to park him at his place.
你就是帕特丽夏吧
You must be Patricia.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
我得走了 得去接山姆
I really have to go. Gotta pick Sam up.
我带他上去
我可以带他上去 没有问题
莫名其妙
你才莫名其妙
你现在可以走了 没关系的
Oh, you can go now. It's alright.
我不会弄坏东西的
I won't nick anything.
倒不是说这有什么东西可弄
Not that there's much to nick.
我信任山姆 山姆信任你
Well, I trust Sam, and Sam trusts you.
但是你不信任我
But you don't trust me.
他过得怎么样?
How is he?
他还好吗?
Is he alright?
我是说 他... 有没有朋友?
I mean, has he got... friends?
你是怎么认识他的 科利尔先生?
How do you know him, Mr Collier?
我在很久很久之前帮助过他
I helped him out a long, long time ago.
你要找谁 孩子?
Who are you looking for, son?
詹姆士・卡拉汉少校 先生
Major James Callaghan, sir.
第二武装部队
2nd AIF.
我很抱歉 孩子 你的父亲不在这里
I'm sorry, son. Your father's not here.
两个月前 他和一个工作组出去了
Went out with a work party, two months ago.
再也没有回来
He never came back.
好吧
OK, then.
等等! 你要去哪里?
Wait! Where are you going?
爸爸说 如果有什么状况 在家里见面
Dad said, anything goes wrong, meet at the house.
他不在那里
He's not there.
他再也没有回来
He never came back.
他再也不会回来了
He's not ever coming back.
他会在家里的!
He'll be at the house!
嘿 康
Hey, Kang.
瞧瞧她们
Look at them.
两个醉鬼
Two drinks.
抱歉!
Sorry!
酒的度数挺高 那又怎样?
Pretty strong drinks. So what?
没那么高 他很厉害
Not that strong. He's good.
我一直在盯着他
I've been looking at him.
我想他在她们的酒里放了点东西
I think he's putting something in their drinks.
罗伯和安吉在这里的那个晚上他在吗?
Was he around the night Robbo and Ange were here?
我不能确定 但是...
I can't swear it, but...
嘿! 你在干什么?
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
嘿 你误会了 好吗?
Hey, OK, you got it wrong, OK?
- 你误会了 - 是吗?
- You got it wrong. - Yeah?
她们是我的朋友 我只是在试着帮助她们
They're my friends. I'm just trying to help them.
- 帮助她们? - 有点不对劲
- Help them out? - Something wrong.
你在周二晚上帮助别人了吗
Help anyone else out Tuesday night?
一个黑人男子和白人女孩?
A black guy and a white girl?
什么? 没有!
What? No!
你帮助她早早地进了坟墓
You helped her into an early grave.
- 那个女孩死了 - 什么?
- That girl died. - What?
- 你带着刀子了吗? - 什么?
- You carry a knife? - What?
- 我不会问你两遍  - 没有!
- Not gonna ask you again.- No!
好吗 那不是我干的
OK, it wasn't me.
你抓错人了 好吗?
You got the wrong guy, OK?
你掺了他们的酒 不是吗?
You spiked their drinks, didn't you?
是的 是的
Yeah, yeah.
你跟着他们出来了 他们也像这样吗?
You followed them out. Were they like that?
不不不 我没有到那一步 好吗?
No, no, no. OK, I didn't get that far, right?
他们和某人起了冲突 吵得很凶
They bump into someone and there was a big argument.
那是谁?
Who was that?
我不知道 一个挺强硬的家伙
I don't know. Tough guy.
你知道 阴沉着脸
You know, not happy-looking face.
我不知道他是谁 我没逗留很久
I don't know who the hell he is, right, but I didn't stay too long.
然后我就回到酒吧了 仅此而已 好吗?
I just go back to my bar. That's all. Right?
现在你要进监狱了
Well, now you're going to jail.
阿姨!
Aunty!
不是 对不...
Ah, no. Excu...
抱歉 我没想吓你
Sorry, I didn't mean to alarm you,
但是在山姆那里没什么事情可做
but there's nothing much to do over at Sam's place,
所以我过来 看看有没有我能做的事
so I thought I'd come over and see if there's anything I can do.
山姆认识他
是他干的吗?
So is he the one?
貌似不是
Doesn't look like it.
阿姆兰说他以前做过这种事
Amran said he's done this kind of thing before.
但他没有谋杀的迹象
But he's got no form for murder.
不过至少高度酒
Well, at least the drink spiking
解释了我朋友为什么都不记得了
explains why your friend can't remember anything.
但也不能说明不是他杀的啊
Doesn't mean he didn't kill her.
他喝醉了 想做爱
He's drunk, wants sex.
她拒绝了
She say no.
有时候毒品会使人疯狂
Well, sometimes drugs makes you crazy.
嘿 嘘!
Hey, shh!
话说 和他们吵架的那个人你觉得是谁?
So, anyway, who do you think that tough guy was that they fought with?
也许就是闯进安吉公寓的那个人
Maybe it's the same guy who broke into Ange's apartment.
这之间一定有联系
It's gotta be connected.
那我猜我们应该在喧闹的唐人街逛一逛
I guess we just wander through busy Chinatown looking for a guy
找一下哪个人没了耳垂
with a missing earlobe, then.
如果有必要的话 只能这样了
Well, if that's what it takes, yeah.
她很出色
She was good.
她的文章 调查 意见
The writing, the research, the voice.
确实很出色
She was really good.
当然 她还年轻
I mean, she was still young.
暂时得不到什么奖
She wasn't going to win any prizes, yet.
但她绝对有这潜力
But she was certainly on her way.
不过她也很愚蠢
And she was also nuts.
一个人深夜去码头 去和毒贩交谈
Down at the docks late at night, by herself, talking to dealers.
她做得比我想象得还要深入
And she went much further than I realised.
调查居民 毒贩 各种动向
People. Deals, movements.
查到什么人了吗?
Any names?
是的 查到一个
Yeah, there is a name.
他是个毒贩
He's a dealer.
是他把大麻卖给她的
He's the bloke she bought the hash from.
是罗伯吗?
Is it Robbo?
不是
No.
他名叫莱昂内尔・章
His name's Lionel Cheong.
他在码头有一间小屋
He's got a shack down at the docks.
她把向他买毒品的过程描述得很清楚
She describes exactly how you buy drugs from him.
大叔派我来的
他说你的鱼今天很新鲜
看看我们抓到谁了
Oh, look who we got here today.
他承认卖毒品给安吉
He's admitted to selling drugs to Ange
还试图把它偷回来 你还需要什么信息吗?
and trying to steal them back, so what else do you want?
他也许怕你打他就乱说一气
He probably said anything to stop you hitting him.
得了 我们碰都没碰他 他可能就是凶手
Come on, we hardly touched the guy. He could be the killer.
他这么说了吗?
Did he say so?
他不会承认的 不是吗?
He's not going to admit it, is he?
那个给他们下药的人说有看见他们和别人争吵
The guy who spiked their drinks says he saw them argue with someone.
这家伙脱不了干系
This guy's connected.
有个小问题
Slight problem.
那人两天前被警方锁定 整晚都被监视着
Two nights ago that man was in police lock-up. All night.
他不可能是凶手
He couldn't be the killer.
那把刀呢? 你们找到了吗?
So what about the knife? You found that yet?
是的 找到了
Yeah, we did.
在那个姑娘公寓后面的巷子里
In the back alley near the girl's apartment.
离我们抓到你朋友的地方很近
Close to where we picked up your friend.
依我看 是他在发现警察来抓他的时候
As I thought, he must have dumped it
把刀丢在那里的
when he saw the police coming for him.
你怎么知道是他的刀?
How do you know it's his knife?
刀柄上有一串数字
It has numbers on the handle.
- 4965... - 43
- 4965... - 43.
是的
Yeah.
那是罗伯的服役号
That's Robbo's service number.
- 搞定了 - 修好了吗?
- There you go. - Looking good?
是的 应该是好了
Yeah, that should do it.
来 试试
Here, try that one.
天哪 真合适 谢谢你
Oh, my God, it fits so perfectly. Thank you.
不客气
No worries.
请用
Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在船上工作吗?
So you work on the ships?
你就是那样认识山姆的吗?
So that's how you know Sam?
在他做进出口工作时?
From his import-export work?
不 不是的 我...
Well, no, not exactly. I...
我很久以前就认识他了
I've known him for a long time.
警察先生
Inspector.
有何贵干?
What is your business here?
罗伯特・安德鲁・科利尔 我是来逮捕你的
Robert Andrew Collier, I'm placing you under arrest.
但他刚被保释出狱
But he's just been released on bail.
我们有新证据了
We have new evidence.
保释被驳回了
Bail's been revoked.
请站起来
Stand up, please.
嘿 嘿 站住!
Hey, hey, stop!
站住!
Stop!
你让我像是个傻瓜一样
You made me look like a dick.
走了那么多关系 托人帮忙 安排保释
Pulled all these strings, called in favours, organised bail.
可你的朋友却畏罪潜逃
Now your mate's done a runner.
不是他干的 先生
Sir, he didn't do it.
那他为什么要逃?
Well, why did he run, hmm?
正如我们所说 现在你的另一朋友又要在公爵
Now your other mate's down at the Duke as we speak
炮制下一个大新闻
banging out his next big story.
我都不敢去想明天的头条会是什么
I don't even want to guess what the headline is,
但我猜'土著居民'和'畏罪潜逃'
but I would suspect that 'Aborigine' and 'walkabout'
会是关键词
will feature fairly largely.
听着 如果你坚信他是清白的
Look, if you are convinced this man is innocent,
那就找些证据出来
then find some bloody evidence.
我可以告诉你的是
And I can tell you this.
如果是他杀害了那个澳大利亚女孩
If he's murdered an Australian girl,
那战争英雄的头衔也救不了他
being a war hero will not help him.
等等 你去哪?
Wait. Where are you going?
爸爸说 如果情况有变 就在家里碰头
Dad said, if anything goes wrong, meet at the house.
你不能待在这
You can't stay here.
这里没有吃的
There's no food.
我能找到吃的
I can get food.
这人是谁?
Who this man?
你又是谁?
Who the hell are you?
他是翁叔叔 我一直问他要吃的
This is Uncle Weng. I've been getting food off him.
从战俘监狱里来的?
From the camp?
你从战俘监狱溜到城市里来的?
You snuck into the city from the prison camp?
总得有人这么做
Someone had to.
我要回店里去了
I've got to get back to the shop.
你一个人没问题吗?
You sure you're OK?
你这样过多久了?
How long you been doing this?
自从妈妈被杀后就一直这样过了
Since Mum got murdered.
看来你还真不愧是个侦探 对吧?
So you really are some sort of detective, eh?
我想如果我是个好侦探 我就应该先来这里
I suppose if I were any good, I would have come here first.
知道吗 当你第一次带我来这时
You know, when you first brought me here,
我以为你在战争前
I thought that you must have been
一定是个被宠坏的小家伙
one hell of a spoilt brat before the war.
所以你才无法面对
Thought that's why you couldn't face the fact
爸爸回不了家这一事实
that your dad wasn't coming home.
你总是有你自己的行事方式
I mean, you always had your own way.
是的
Yeah.
现在我觉得真相很难去面对...
Now I'm thinking truth can be a hard thing to face...
...不管你是四五年时的小伙
...whether you're a young lad in '45
还是六四年时的老兵
or an old soldier in '64.
那你准备怎么办? 回到船上吗?
So what do you wanna do? Get back on the boat?
船今晚就开
Ship sails tonight.
船长是我的朋友
The captain's a mate.
他能帮我移民出去
He can get me through immigration.
那你就再也回不来了
You could never come back.
是的
The truth.
你有计划?
You got a plan?
是的
Yeah.
那就赶快开始吧
Then you'd better get cracking.
你到这来里来过 记得吗?
So you came here. You remember that?
是的 虽然不是很清楚
Yeah, it's not clear as day.
但回忆起来不是问题
But that's not the bit I'm having problems with.
你们做了些什么?
And what were you doing?
安吉和我在外面买了些东西吃
Well, Ange and I got something to eat outside,
我喂她吃鸡爪
and I fed her a chook's foot.
然后进来喝酒除除味道
And we came in here to wash the taste out.
你记得和谁说过话吗?
Do you remember talking to someone?
年轻的马来人?
Young Malay bloke?
没有
No.
我认为他在你们酒里下了药
I think he spiked your drink.
好吧 这之后呢?
Alright, what happened after that?
安吉觉得头有点晕
Well, Ange was feeling a little dizzy.
我们就出去透透气
We went out to get some fresh air.
- 你们这就出去了? - 是的
- So you left? - Yeah.
好的 那你们走的哪条路?
OK, so which way did you go?
从这走的
Ah, through this way.
有只 猴子在跳舞
There was, er, a monkey dancing in the street.
那边
That way.
她说这是近路
She said it was a short cut.
有几个人在这里赌博
There was a bunch of guys gambling through here.
这扇门
This door.
那个炒面男
The chow mein guy.
什么?
The what?
炒面男 他在这里
The chow mein guy, he was there.
- 有打斗吗? - 不 不 没那回事
- Was it a fight? - Oh, no, no, nothing like that.
我们继续走
We just kept on walking.
就这样了
And that's it.
我能记起的下一件事 就是我在她身边醒来
Next thing I know, I woke up next to her.
一定还有其他的情况
There's got to be something else.
安吉家在拐角处
Ange's place is around the corner.
肯定有什么事在这里发生
Whatever it was had to have happened here.
就在这里
Right here.
听着 这是个好主意
Look, it was a good idea.
- 好方法 - 继续想 罗伯 拜托了
- A good try. - Keep thinking, Robbo. Come on.
你在这里 安吉在这里
You were here, Ange was here.
也许我不想查出真相
Maybe I don't want to find out.
也许是我干的
Maybe I did it.
也许除了这点什么也发现不了
Maybe there's nothing to find out except that.
也许是你干的
Maybe you did.
你不想确定一下吗?
Don't you want to know for sure?
怎么了?
What is it?
想起一些东西
Something.
她休息了一下
She rested.
安吉
Ange.
安吉在这里休息
Ange rested here.
当时我在这里
And I was here.
炒面男
The chow mein guy.
你的包!
Your bag!
别管它了
Don't worry about it.
你还好吗?
You OK?
我们回... 家吧
Let's get... home.
我没想到有那么严重
I didn't realise it was that serious.
你不可能知道的
Well, you couldn't have known.
我本可以做点什么的
Well, I could have done something.
- 我本可以求助的 - 不过你被下药了
- I could have called for help. - But you were drugged.
你没杀他 罗伯 是这个人干的
You didn't kill her, Robbo. This other guy did.
就因为我们撞到了他?
Because we bumped him?
只是运气不好罢了
It was just bad luck.
错误的时间错误的地点
Wrong place at the wrong time.
你记得他的相貌吗?
You remember his face?
是的 我记得
Yeah, I remember his face.
下午好 哈里森 进展得怎么样了?
Good afternoon, Harrison. How did you get on?
我拿到你想要的东西了
I got what you wanted.
太棒了
Excellent.
我会继续做你交给我的事
And I'm going to keep on doing as you ask.
不过我知道你的本质...
But I see you for what you are...
一个虚伪卑鄙的英国佬
a slimy limey turd.
我真心希望你趁太阳还没下山
I really hope that you enjoy the sunshine
好好欣赏阳光
while it lasts,
因为总有一天 农奴会翻身做主人的
because one day the boot's going to be on the other foot.
好像是那个人
That looks like him.
你记得我吗?
You remember me?
整件事不过是一个很遗憾的故事
The whole thing's just a sorry story.
他生气了 赶上他们 想抢走安吉的包
I mean, he got angry, went after 'em, tried to snatch Ange's bag.
她没意识到她伤得多严重
She didn't realise how badly she'd been hurt.
- 这故事不错 - 搜搜他的住所
- Good story. - Search his apartment.
说不定能找到她的包
Maybe you'll find her bag.
你把刀扫描了吗?
You pull any prints off the knife?
我肯定上面全是方的指纹
I bet Fong's are all over it.
是他干的 阿姆兰
He's the one, Amran.
不是罗伯
Not Robbo.
- 你朋友确定是那个人? - 对
- Your friend's sure it was that guy? - Oh, yeah.
- 我会调查清楚的 - 好的
- I'll look into it. - OK.
真为你朋友高兴
Very pleased for your mate.
你可以自己告诉他啊
Well, you could tell him yourself.
你也知道 我有好多事要干
Oh, well, you know, so much to do.
邮件 外交函件啊
Mail, diplomatic correspondence.
另外 我得给这个女孩的父母写一份官方报告
Plus, I need to write an official report for the girl's parents.
不过拜托你 把我的问候带给他
But please, give the man my best.
罗伯特・科利尔
Robert Collier.
对 没错 是科利尔
Yes, Collier. Exactly.
她们来了
Ah. Here they are.
现在 她们要过来喝点开胃酒了
Now, they will be down here for an aperitif shortly.
你想留下来吗?
Would you care to stay?
不行 我要去见一个人
Oh, I can't. I'm meeting someone.
真聪明啊
Wise man.
接下来的事 我们称之为外交事件
Now, there's what you call a diplomatic incident.
要是你想跟小白脸鬼混
If you're going to go wild with the pool boy,
老天 可千万别告诉你丈夫
for God's sake, don't tell the husband.
不论如何 再次谢谢你 卡拉汉
Anyhow, thanks again, Callaghan.
安吉 她是个好女孩
She was a good girl, Ange.
很聪明
Bright.
她面前有大好的前程
She had the whole world in front of her.
我不敢相信她已经死了
I can't believe she's dead.
就因为 有个家伙 这...
All because what, some bloke, what...
这叫什么 命该如此还是只是运气不好?
What's that, fate or just dumb luck?
不管是什么
Whatever it is,
它让你在四五年的时候为我停下来了
it made you stop for me in '45.
一路顺风 大哥
Sail well, brother.
谢谢 兄弟
Thanks, mate.
你的朋友正式清白了
Your friend's officially in the clear.
李库方被控告了
Lee Kum Fong's been charged.
我们在他的住所找到了女孩的包
We found the girl's handbag at his place.
下药的人应该能找到他
The drink spiker was able to ID him.
关于指纹你也说对了
And you were right about those prints.
你听上去很惊讶
You sound surprised.
我以为你想让方进监狱
Well, I thought you might have your own reasons
可能有你自己的原因
for wanting Fong in jail.
- 为什么? - 杀害温斯顿的凶手
- Why? - Winston's murder.
李库方是其中一个嫌疑人
Lee Kum Fong was one of the suspects.
那晚有人看见他在现场 这是他的风格
He was seen in the area that night. It's his style.
杯子里藏了把刀
Mugging with a knife.
我不确定他是唯一的嫌疑人
I wasn't too sure and he wasn't the only suspect.
不过我已经盯上他了
But I had my eye on him.
你认为李库方杀了温斯顿・郑?
You think Lee Kum Fong killed Winston Cheng?
我觉得有这个可能
I think it's possible.
我们查了温斯顿被杀时正在调查的所有案件
We've been going back through all the cases Winston was working on
没提到方啊
when he was killed, and there was no mention of Fong.
第一次 我们有了嫌疑人
Well, for the first time, we've got a suspect.
方可能是唯一一个
Fong could be the only person who knows
知道当晚温斯顿情况的人
what happened to Winston that night.
我们得从他开始
We've got to start with him.
明天一早我就去找他谈
I'll talk to him first thing tomorrow.
好的
Yeah, alright.
山姆?
Oh, Sam?
你朋友 辛普森夫人
Um, your friend, Mrs Simpson.
我听说她要离开新加坡了
I've heard she's leaving Singapore.
你知道这事儿吗?
Do you know that?
明天一早
First thing tomorrow morning.
好了 抱歉耽误了这么久
Here you go. Sorry that took so long.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
嘿
Hey.
山姆?
Sam?
她在这吗?
Is she here?
要是我告诉你她在呢?
And what if I told you that she was?
山姆
Oh, Sam.
你能给她带来什么呢?
I mean, what can you offer her?
什么 唐人街的一个房间?
What is it, a room in Chinatown?
她失去了她的婚姻 她的家庭 她的朋友
She'd lose her marriage, her family, her friends.
她没有工作
She'd have no job.
我是说 她能怎么做呢?
I mean, what would she do?
你知道 要是你真的爱她...
You know, if you really love her...
...你也许应该想想怎么做对她最好
...you might consider just doing what's best for her.
我不会告诉她你来过
I won't tell her that you were here.
重要的不是你这么做了
It's not that you did it.
而是他拿什么威胁你让你这么做的
It's whatever he's got on you that made you do it.
我在建议他们把你安排到别的地方
I'm recommending they post you somewhere else.
对不起我对你撒谎了
I'm sorry that I lied to you.
如果我问你一个问题 是想得到诚实的答案
If I ask you a question, I expect an honest answer.
日安 弗兰克
G'day, Frank.
周五晚上 我们会永远离开新加坡
On Friday night, we're leaving Singapore for good.
我们会坐船去欧洲并且不会再回来
We're going to Europe by ship and we're not coming back.
齐基特的办公室 齐基特和温斯顿认识对方
Chee Kit's office. Chee Kit and Winston knew each other.
我相信我哥哥跟一些危险人物有联系
I believe my brother was involved with some dangerous people.
一切还好吗 林先生?
Everything alright, Mr Lim?
这是我找出杀害我丈夫的凶手的机会
This is my chance to find out who killed my husband.